This holiday season, be Italian.
Nine is a drama, music, romance film directed by Rob Marshall.
Arrogant, self-centered movie director Guido Contini finds himself struggling to
find meaning, purpose, and a script for his latest film endeavor.
With only a week left before shooting begins, he desperately searches for answers and
inspiration from his wife, his mistress, his muse, and his mother.
Guido Contini, played by Daniel Day-Lewis.
Luisa Contini, played by Marion Cotillard.
Carla, played by Penélope Cruz.
Claudia, played by Nicole Kidman.
Lilli, played by Judi Dench.
Mamma, played by Sophia Loren.
Nine is a 2009 romantic musical drama film directed and co-produced by Rob Marshall from a screenplay by Michael Tolkin and
Anthony Minghella, loosely based on the musical of the same name, which in turn is based on the film 8½.
In addition to songs from the stage musical, all written by Maury Yeston, the film has three original
songs, also written by Yeston ("Take It All", "Cinema Italiano", and "Guarda La Luna").
The ensemble cast includes Daniel Day-Lewis, Marion Cotillard, Penélope Cruz,
Judi Dench, Fergie, Kate Hudson, Nicole Kidman, and Sophia Loren.
Nine premiered at the Dubai International Film Festival on December 9, 2009, and had a limited release in New York City and
Los Angeles on December 18, with a wide release in the United States on December 25, by The Weinstein Company.
Though the film received mixed reviews from critics, the cast and
especially Marion Cotillard's performance were praised.
Nine was nominated for four Academy Awards: Best Supporting Actress (Penélope Cruz), Best Production Design (John
Myhre and Gordon Sim), Best Costume Design (Colleen Atwood), and Best Original Song ("Take It All").
The film explores themes of creative crisis,
melancholy, musical, memory, sidewalk cafe.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.